[Flourished Peony]
[Episode 15]
Come on. That's enough.
Don't scare the young lady.
Old man,
I'm not the one who started the scare.
Back then, I could berate people to death.
Now, I can terrify them to death.
You two, who are as good as dead,
are quite a pair.
Upon hearing someone coming,
you will rush into the cabinet,
acting like monkeys.
You should call me teacher.
You're not a ghost.
You aren't dead.
Your master-disciple relationship
was severed long ago, wasn't it?
Didn't you treat each other as enemies?
What's going on?
Indeed.
If our relationship hadn't been severed,
and given that we're like oil and water,
could he have lived until today?
I see.
The man you killed that day wasn't Master Xu.
My teacher is dedicated to public service,
and strikes the Prince Ning's sore spot.
I went to my teacher's house that night
to discuss the matter.
However, he had not returned
for a long time.
I was afraid something bad
would happen, so I went out.
I did not expect Prince Ning
was so impatient.
Fortunately, it was raining heavily,
and the river was swollen.
So I used a corpse
with a physique and age similar
to my teacher's, in a bait-and-switch.
That night, Prince Ning
didn't get assassin's reply.
He also asked people to search.
But his men found nothing.
They only saw
the rolling river over the bank.
Not until the next day,
were the bodies of them
fished out from the water.
They were unrecognizable.
Therefore, the coroner could only identify them
by their clothing, accessories,
body shape and teeth.
Prince Ning was satisfied
and didn't look into it further.
He believed my fake
that the assassin and the guards
were both supposedly killed.
The incident happened all of a sudden.
Had it not been for your timely arrival
and meticulous response,
I truly fear
I would have perished.
You have won the hearts of the people,
and are highly respected
by the virtuous students.
Prince Ning will not allow you to live.
I can save you for a while,
but not for the rest of your life.
And then I have to employ a countermeasure.
They are confidential.
Why do you divulge everything to me?
I was just testing you.
Seeing that you are righteous and honest,
I decide to give you a way out.
My teacher, posing as a servant,
is recuperating at Jiang Mansion
out of sheer necessity.
However, whether it's Jiang Mansion
or Huanyun Tower,
there are too many high-ranking officials.
If this continues for long,
trouble is bound to arise sooner or later.
I see.
Master Xu,
if you don't mind,
you can move into my store.
West Market is a place for the common people,
not for the rich and famous.
I can arrange for you
to live in a private room,
hidden away from the city.
As long as you're a bit careful,
you won't be discovered.
That would naturally be good.
Having to share a roof
with this little rascal,
I'll either be killed
or die from rage eventually.
Of course, I won't
live off you without contributing.
I'm good at calculations.
How about I
serve as an accountant for you?
I wouldn't dare.
You're the Master of the Imperial Academy.
How can you be an accountant for me?
If I miscalculate,
you can ask him for money.
Without you,
she hasn't stopped asking me for money.
And now with you included,
she could bleed the Jiang Mansion dry.
If that is the case,
Master Xu, please come with me.
Hold on.
Chuanyu.
In here.
There's the powder
for his foot bath and massage,
plus the tea he needs to drink
every day right after rising.
Come back for more after you've used it up.
So attentive.
The old man is still of use.
Your life is on credit with me.
Take good care of him.
If you let him get injured or sick,
I will
claim your life back with interest.
Mr. Jiang, you can rest assured.
I'm a person who values life the most.
Alright. Master Xu,
Li Xing is my cousin.
He is also your student.
He grieved day and night after your death.
Now that you're well.
Can you tell him?
No, you can't tell him.
Although Li Xing is sincere,
he is too simple to be deceitful.
If he slips up after knowing,
I will have to
kill another innocent man.
Stop scaring her.
If you keep scaring her,
I'll kill you, too.
Some matters are fraught with danger.
For Li Xing's safety,
it's better not to tell him.
I get it.
Give me the dry grass.
Be careful.
No problem.
Come on. Have some water.
Thank you, Shengyi.
A few days ago,
you were talking about how troublesome it is
to live at other's mercy.
In the blink of an eye,
a pavilion has been erected.
Aren't we moving out?
I think moving
is just too much of a hassle.
It would be better to make this place
more comfortable and cozy,
and treat it like home.
With this pavilion,
we can use it for relaxing and taking breaks.
Mudan,
why do you suddenly bring back
an accountant
and place him in the shop.
You don't let anyone bother him.
Are you mad at me
because I made a few miscalculations earlier?
Not at all.
I see you are really too busy on a daily basis,
and find someone to help you.
Mr. Xu
is skilled at abacus.
I spend a lot of money
to poach him from another shop.
I usually keep him hidden,
fearing the original owner might find out
and come here to cause a scene.
Once he takes over the accounts,
and secures the rear,
we can then withdraw.
While when it comes to dealing with people
and managing the flower business,
I still have to rely on you.
Okay.
This time, with the help
of the imperial tutor's last wish,
and the support of the Ministry of Rites,
the imperial examination has been revitalized.
Although it's impossible
to achieve purely merit-based appointments,
at least the number of commoners
entering officialdom has been changed to
a ratio of three to seven.
These students from humble backgrounds
now have hopes of rising up.
Previously, when I went to Luoyang,
I sponsored many students
from humble backgrounds.
Now they are studying hard
in peace at the Fuyun Temple.
Upon learning of this news,
all of them are filled with lofty ambitions.
How about the Integrity Society
that assassinates corrupt officials?
They have already been subdued
and educated by me.
In the future, we'll leave it to them
to rescue the students of private schools
who are bullied by the scholarly families.
Master Xu feigned death to escape.
It was truly an act of helplessness.
Though the civil officials
have lost their backing,
they can use the reform as an opportunity
to restructure the forces in the court.
When the time is ripe in the future,
Master Xu will reappear.
He can prove Prince Ning killed the loyalists.
You've been scheming and maneuvering,
trying to turn the tables
in a losing situation.
Unfortunately, when you deal with tigers,
you're also regarded as a wolf.
You're wronged.
Who could wrong me?
Whether it's the curses
of the students at the Imperial Academy,
or the satirical poems of Li Xing.
In my opinion,
I just think them interesting.
Being a greedy official with a notorious name
is more pleasant and relaxed
than suffering miserably
and enduring hardships
for the sake of revenge, right?
Besides, the Prince Ning's associates
blatantly commit acts of corruption and bribery
without any secrecy around me.
In the future, when we have to deal with them,
we'll avoid a lot of the hassle
of gathering proof of their misdeeds.
You're so open-minded.
You're willing to risk your reputation
to uphold justice.
Such a broad-minded attitude
is beyond our reach.
Re-examining the officials
responsible for the selections
can remove some corrupt bureaucrats,
but with regard to Prince Ning,
yet it fails to harm his essence.
That impeached Minister Cui,
in reality, is placed in
the Ministry of Personnel by Prince Ning
to help Prince Ning manipulate
the appointing and dismissal of officials.
He still has countless connections
with various noble families,
but he just refuses
to reveal who's behind all this.
Although he has been sentenced to exile now,
it hasn't caused any stir.
It has just been glossed over like that.
What a pity.
It won't be a pity.
The Ministry of Justice acts
in accordance with the law.
Prince Ning has sent his men
to keep an eye on it.
Clearly, the investigation will yield nothing.
But when it comes to Jiang Mansion,
it's a different story.
Hurry up! Keep up!
Everyone behind, keep up!
Go! Follow up!
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
Sir.
I'm suddenly in excruciating abdominal pain.
Considering the post station is still far away,
could you allow me
to relieve myself?
You go with him. No tricks.
Don't try anything. Go.
The rest of you get down!
Hurry up!
Right here.
Don't try anything. Hurry up!
Are you done there?
Hurry up! We have to go.
Keep running if death doesn't scare you.
Let's see if you can run fast,
or my knife is faster.
My hero.
I don't know if you are friend or foe.
I have a fortune.
As long as you are willing to save me,
I can offer it all.
Well, coincidentally.
The last thing I need is money.
The customers
who make a credit purchase at Huamanzhu
are really quite a few.
To prevent customers from not paying
and not being able to find them,
it's better to stipulate
that regular customers
who spend over a hundred strings
must leave their household register.
Only after verifying and signing
can they be allowed to buy on credit.
We should settle accounts
at the end of the month.
Your words are very true.
However, Master Xu.
You are the Master of the Imperial Academy.
You are also Mr. Jiang's
and my cousin's respected teacher.
Your visit here is merely to avoid disaster.
There's no need for you
to personally toil over these.
A small clue reveals the general trend.
You think I'm just
looking at the accounts of a small flower shop.
Not at all.
Only when people live and work
in peace and contentment,
will the citizens be willing to spend money
on buying a flower and a whiff of fragrance.
What I'm concerned with
are taxes and the people's livelihood.
I've taken the lesson.
The house is a bit small
and the orientation isn't great.
The arrangement is passable, at best.
It's really an inconvenience to you.
Since the shop opened,
it's the first time Mr. Jiang has come here
to inspect in person.
Are you afraid that I'll neglect Mr. Xu,
or are you here on purpose?
The investor not visiting the store
is because I trust you.
If you don't appreciate it,
I suppose you won't want
the celebratory present
I've prepared for you today.
Chuanyu, let's go.
You are as noble as an orchid
with a broad-minded spirit.
How could I not welcome you?
You're here.
Why did you spend so much money?
Such an exquisite scroll.
Which master's work is it?
Peony
[Peony is useless]
is useless?
These four characters are written
as smoothly as flowing clouds
and running water, all in one go.
They really have a touch
of the great calligrapher Zhang Zhi's style.
Thanks for your compliment.
[Peony is Useless]
The peony has long been off the market.
Mr. Jiang, this gift is a bit late, isn't it?
Isn't there a Mudan standing before me?
Why don't you hang it
in a prominent place in your store?
It's a good reminder for you
to always look at yourself and remember
the kindness of your investor.
Are you insulting me, Mr. Jiang?
Or are you here to make trouble?
This is a truly genuine
master's calligraphy and painting.
When you snatched it just now,
weren't you overjoyed?
My lord excels in calligraphy.
Normally, literati and connoisseurs
would throng here,
ready to spend a fortune
to get their hands on one.
It's a unique treasure,
beyond price in the marketplace.
You should take good care of it.
If you don't like it so much,
forget it and give it back to me.
No. If you give it to me,
I'll pawn it and sell it,
but I won't give it back to you.
Since you've accepted it,
you must appreciate it.
I wish you good luck
with your business, pay on time,
and take care of my teacher.
I'm leaving now.
Master Xu, please take a look.
Every time I think
he still has a conscience,
he has to do something
that makes me want to fight him with a knife.
The student of yours
changes faces like an actor in Sichuan opera.
His face is changeable.
Is he virtuous or vicious?
Honest or sly?
A spawn of a monster
or with a heart of cold stone?
A man who happily accepts
a bad name for himself,
not seeing it as a hardship
but finding joy in it.
What kind of person
would you say he is?
An idiot.
- Have a nice day and come back soon.
- Okay.
Come in and take a look.
This is what you bought
from our store last time, right?
Yes. I come to discover something new.
Come in.
She completely resolves the issue
about the fertilizer ban,
and even hires landless farmers
for the fertilizer work.
The flower fertilizer in her hands
is not only sufficient for self-sufficiency,
but also for sale
at prices lower than elsewhere.
Our flower guild's fertilizer business
has suddenly dropped by nearly twenty percent.
She is determined
to go against the flower guild.
Alright.
Since she doesn't appreciate kindness,
and then don't blame me for being rude.
Come on.
This is a good idea.
Should we report it to Guild Head Lv?
Such a trivial matter
is not worth bothering the guild head.
Just do as I say.
Yes.
There are no festivals lately.
Why is the Jiang Mansion so lively?
In the backyard,
they are putting on a grand opera performance.
Just don't ruin our flowers.
Let's take a look.
I
have long admired
your poetic and artistic talents.
Although we have met only thrice,
I know in my heart
that the beauty is not here,
and I'm not sure who I'd rather be with.
I boldly seek to marry you.
If I could engage you as my wife
to forever share our common interests,
I'm ready to dismiss all my housemaids.
I will never take a concubine,
nor will I have any lovers.
I will only be with you,
facing each other day and night,
until our hair turns white.
Mr. Jiang comes from a prestigious family.
Without multiple wives and concubines,
people might criticize him
for having too few descendants.
Though there are countless beauties
in the world,
my heart is set on only one.
If you're not by my side in this life.
Chuanyu,
who is Jiang Yuantang?
He is my lord's father.
Madam's death anniversary is approaching.
The person has come fawning over eagerly.
I didn't realize his father
was so devoted.
In an ordinary wealthy family,
there would also be
many concubines and pretty maids.
However, it was not easy for the Jiang family,
which had been officials for many generations,
to favor his wife without concubines.
Having Feng Ruoxin as a wife,
their marital bond was profound and lasting.
While she was alive,
the Jiang Mansion had no beautiful concubines.
Even after her death,
Jiang Yuantang remained a widower.
This tale of devotion has spread far and wide,
earning the envy of all.
Hurry up.
Mr. Jiang.
Madam Feng's
50th death anniversary is approaching.
I know that in her lifetime,
she loved watching puppet plays.
I specially wrote down the cherished tale
of how your revered parents fell in love,
and hired a troupe to perform it.
Merely desiring to slightly mitigate
your pining for your mother.
A good story and fine skills.
Reward.
Grant each musician and performer 50 strings.
Thank you, Mr. Jiang.
You've presented such a fine play.
How should I thank you?
I only wish to
serve as an official in Chang'an,
and to assist you in any way possible.
I want to serve you faithfully by your side.
T-This is…
Chuanyu,
please draft a document on my behalf
and send it to the Ministry of Personnel.
He corrupts his role, bribes others
and commits evil locally.
- Demote him to the northwest to feed horses.
- Yes.
Mr. Jiang, please tell me
what I've done to offend you.
Mr. Jiang, I have nothing but loyalty.
Please show leniency.
Please show leniency, Mr. Jiang.
My lord has already shown exceptional clemency.
If you dare to make another fuss,
I will ensure you can't walk out of here alive.
Go away.
Mr. Jiang.
This puppet is indeed made with care.
It really does resemble
my mother to some extent.
If you were here today,
you'd likely be furious
to the point of vomiting blood.
It doesn't matter.
At least there's still me in this world.
I will always miss you.
If you miss me as well,
please visit me more in my dreams.
Look at me.
[Memorial Tablet]
What is that smell?
Come on.
I was wondering.
The Jiang Mansion has always only had
the smell of money and incense.
Since when did it smell
like barbecue from the stall?
I think your mansion lacks
a touch of the common life's aroma.
Originally, I wanted to call you
when it was done.
I didn't anticipate that your nose is so keen,
coming here just by the smell.
Sit down and have some.
If it's grilled well,
I won't ask for any reward.
If it's not grilled well,
don't throw me to the northwest to feed horses.
I'm afraid you'd sell off those horses.
This chair is too hard.
Chuanyu,
go fetch a soft cushion.
Yes.
Sit down.
Come on.
Is it because
your mother's death anniversary is approaching,
and you miss her too much
that you are feeling upset?
People say my parents
were in love for a lifetime,
that they were destined for each other,
but I'm the only one who knows
that the so-called happy story was just a joke.
It was that persistent affection
and absolute faithfulness
that caused my mother's lifelong suffering.
It seems the brown-nosing attempts
of that petty official went awry.
So the story that your father
never had a second thought
is false.
Perhaps it's true in the beginning.
When I was little,
my mother played the zither and wrote poetry.
My father played the flute and painted.
How loving they were!
But later on,
our entire family moved to Chang'an.
Amidst the myriad distractions,
he fell in love with someone else.
While everyone knows that
your father never took a concubine, didn't he?
Naturally, he was too embarrassed
to break his promise.
So he took her
as a concubine
and never returned home again.
Once my mother died,
he was eager
to marry that woman.
I had to resort to threatening suicide
to help him maintain
his image of being faithful.
Now,
all has returned to dust,
yet they still want to write plays
to spread the story.
Isn't that funny?
So you tell Prince Ning
you swear not to marry in this life
is also true.
Love is as fleeting as clouds,
and men are fickle
by nature.
But for a woman,
it can ruin her life.
Why cause harm to both others and oneself?
My initial assistance in your divorce
was also with my mother in mind.
I wished so much
that she could release her fixation
and walk away with poise, just as you did.
That way, she wouldn't
have met the fate of passing away from sorrow.
Maybe I'm a person who
can't love others more than myself.
Instead of being confined
to the inner chambers for a whole life,
trying to win my husband's heart
against my will,
vying for his affection with concubines,
and being controlled by my parents-in-law,
I prefer to never marry
and take care of myself.
Even if you're divorced,
while at a young age.
It's hard for a woman to live alone.
As time flies,
the past sorrows are gradually forgotten.
You will regret what you say today,
and wish for a home to rely on.
A place that brings peace of mind
is truly home.
Now I have already had
this comforting little home.
I'm very happy now.
That's incorrect.
You're only slightly older than me.
Why are your commitments binding,
yet mine are filled with remorse?
There are beauties by your side all day long.
I'm afraid your vows are more easily broken.
Care to wager with me?
No problem.
The stakes must be
so enormous that they bankrupt you,
only then is it worthwhile
for me to make this bet.
Then let's bet
100,000 strings.
Let's see whether
your treasury will be emptied
or my Huamanzhu will go out of business.
Set it down in words as a pact.
No shirking the deal.
This is the first time I see someone
so eagerly giving away money.
I shall oblige you.
Wait. I'll fetch the ink and brush.
No need.
I want to see how you sign your name.
Just sign it like this.
[Who marries first is a dog. Suizhi.]
The fire's gone out.
It's all baked.
You're a big man.
Are you actually afraid of fire?
How dare you make fun of women for being alone?
Today, I shall perform for you
a fire-breathing stunt.
Let's test your true bravery, Mr. Jiang.
Jiang Xiaohua, don't be a bully.
You've been bullying me all day,
so I can't bully…?
I'm glad you didn't crush my flowers.
Really?
Where is your fire tong?
No! Don't let my Fire Gold Peony
catch fire.
Where's the fire tong?
Where is it?
The Fire Gold Peony
truly lives up to its reputation.
It's like a fierce blaze,
yet it possesses
a delicate and entrancing beauty.
Didn't you say before
that the peony is useless?
This is not a peony.
It's an herbaceous peony.
It's the herbaceous peony
that chosen by Mr. Third.
You know quite a lot.
For the sake of
the blossoming of Fire Gold Peony,
let's have another drink.
Come on.
It's a cool night. Put it on.
What is this ugly thing?
I don't want it.
It's embroidered in gold thread.
Your favorite gold nuggets.
Gold nuggets.
We have the same hobbies.
Who are you?
Aunt?
Why don't you
tie up him?
- Yes.
[Memorial Tablet]
Kneel down.
I didn't expect
that my beautiful dream would come true.
How dare you move?
Ruoxin would be furious
if she knew that you were lying drunk
with a lady in a flower bush
in broad daylight.
I'll slap you.
Aunt,
I've told you a million times.
We just got drunk
and fell asleep yesterday.
Nothing happened.
She's the floriculturist
who takes care of the flowers in my mansion.
The herbaceous peony in the mansion
is very beautiful this year.
Your work is not bad.
Thank you for your appreciation, Madam Feng.
I'll take the flowers
and my nephew-in-law.
How old are you?
If you don't take a wife this year,
I'll beat you for your mother.
No matter what.
The lady's reputation and innocence
have been ruined by you.
You must give her an explanation.
The betrothal gifts are given today,
and the proposal is made.
The wedding will take place
on the eighth day of the coming month.
It's a highly favorable day.
You've misunderstood.
I have no private relationship
with your nephew.
We are simply
in a monetary relationship.
Rest assured.
A bride price of a thousand gold,
and over a hundred plots of land and shops.
I'll ensure he doesn't
treat you unfairly in terms of money.
That's not what I meant.
Aunt knows how I feel.
Indeed, I've admired Mudan for a long time
I will marry no one but her.
Hey!
Where are you putting your hand?
He is just my creditor.
If you think the money is too much,
you can give me a smaller share.
I can be a fair-weather friend with you.
That's the relationship at best.
Don't even think about
marrying me.
You see, it's not that I don't want to marry.
I have the idea, but she doesn't agree.
My heartfelt love and desire,
converted into a flood of fortune,
yet I never manage to touch the heart of her.
You usually don't…
Mudan,
I'm willing to lower the share
and give you more benefits.
Can you give me a chance?
Alright.
You filthy lecher.
Don't even think about
getting the upper hand over me.
Listen up, if you keep bothering me,
I'll hang
at your door.
Mudan,
If I can't be with the one I love,
I would rather remain unmarried for life.
It seems that I'm doomed to be lonely for life.
She comes from a merchant family,
but she doesn't sell her heart for money.
A good lady.
Over all these years,
I finally see someone daring to hit you.
Don't worry.
I'm determined to have this girl
as your wife.
No. Aunt.
My lord has said that
the contract can be changed to
a thirty-seventy split.
However, Madam Feng is not easy to fool.
Since you've agreed to put on an act,
you must refuse to the end.
You must not give her
any chance to take advantage.
Madam Feng,
no matter how much jewelry you give me,
I will absolutely not agree to this marriage.
Just give up on this idea.
You're misunderstanding.
These gifts are my way
of apologizing for my nephew's
reckless and impertinent behavior.
Whether you like him or not.
You should accept them.
If other ladies were to see me sharing a bed
with Jiang Changyang amidst the flowers,
they'd surely scold me
for acting indecently and being frivolous.
Moreover,
in front of you,
I slapped him.
Don't you think
I'm greedy and cruel?
In the case of a man
and a woman staying together,
if such behavior is deemed
frivolous and senseless,
the man deserves the blame.
What's the achievement
in castigating the woman?
My nephew has always been reckless.
You hit him and scold him.
Well done!
As for being greedy.
You're a businesswoman.
Seeking profit is your instinct.
How can I criticize you?
I didn't expect Jiang Changyang
to have such a considerate and reasonable aunt.
My husband died when I was only 18.
Since then, I never remarried.
In all these years, I've been keeping a fleet
and trading extensively.
I've been to foreign places
and heard plenty of idle talk.
If it weren't for a pair of eyes
that can distinguish truth from fallacy
and not be intimidated by common customs,
I wouldn't have lived to this day.
In this world,
a woman's life is truly not easy.
We should help and understand each other.
♫ In endless Chang'an,
the zither's melody distant ♫
♫ Plum and willow trees bask in the sunshine,
as splendor returns with the year ♫
♫ Copper palace battlements,
songs and dances, glass goblets ♫
♫ Idle clouds and duckweed,
a thousand flowers burst forth ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫
♫ The distant night sky strewn with stars,
reflecting the lovely moon ♫
♫ The peony's magnificent beauty
fills the Fragrance Garden ♫
♫ With a heart as my lantern,
I don't mind the distant mountain paths ♫
♫ The flute's sound,
a fleeting life's wishes fulfilled ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫